Register of the Theodore W. Bogacz writings
Hoover Institution Archives
Theodore W. Bogacz writings
1976-1984
96050
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
The Theodore W. Bogacz papers consist of writings and correspondence relating to the American academic Theodore Bogacz. The writings center on British cultural responses to World War I and include his doctoral dissertation ?Sassoon and Company: Siegfrid Sassoon?s Journey to Modernity in the Great War? (University of California, Berkeley, 1982).
Bogacz, Theodore W.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1943 Born
1980 Appointed to faculty of the U.S. Naval Academy at Annapolis, Maryland
1982 Awarded doctorate by the University of California at Berkeley
1986-1987 Taught as exchange professor at the British Royal Military College at Sandhurst, England
1992 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The Theodore W. Bogacz papers consist of writings and correspondence relating to the American academic Theodore Bogacz. The writings center on British cultural responses to World War I and include his doctoral dissertation ?Sassoon and Company: Siegfrid Sassoon?s Journey to Modernity in the Great War? (University of California, Berkeley, 1982). The papers also include shorter essays published between the years of 1976 and 1989. Among these are a study of what Bogacz calls ?war neurosis? in England during World War I as well as an assessment of English painters during the period 1914-1932.
Arrangement Statement
Collection is organized into 2 series: Correspondence; and Writings
Sassoon, Siegfried, 1886-1967.; Art--Great Britain.; British literature.; World War, 1914-1918--Art and the war.; World War, 1914-1918--Literature and the war.
- Correspondence, 1984
  - Stansky, Peter, 1984 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Writings, 1976-1989
  - "Escape from Mortmere: The Left-Wing Writers of the 1930s and the Public School System" and commentary by Louis R. Biscaglia, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - "Sassoon and Company: Siegfrid Sassoon's Journey to Modernity in the Great War,", 1982
    - Chapters 1-3, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Chapter 4, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Chapter 5, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Chapter 6, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Chapter 7 and Notes, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - "Language, Poetry and Anti-Modernism in the First World War: The English Case,", 1983 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - "War Neurosis and Cultural Change in England: The Work of the War Office Committee of Enquiry Into 'Shell-Shock',", 1984 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - "English Painters at War: Traditionalists, Visionaries, and the Avant-Garde, 1914-1932,", 1989 (Box-folder 1: 10)